Rhode Island Conference of the United Church of Christ records, 1812-2019.
Congregational Library & Archives
- Conference records, 1839 2019; 1839-2019; 8 Volumes; 114 Folders
  - Administrative records, 1863 2018; 1863-2018; 5 Volumes; 41 Folders
    - Conference minister resignation, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Southern New England Conference proposal, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Tri-conference annual meeting, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Tri-conference annual meeting, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Transitional conference minister, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - "Together as One" annual meeting, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Rhode Island Home Missionary Society John F. Huntsman address, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Floppy disks, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Ministerial records, 1923 1959; 1923-1959; 4 Folders
    This subseries contains correspondence and other records related to ministers within the conference.
    - General ministerial correspondence, 1923 1947; 1923-1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ministerial credentials, 1928 1948; 1928-1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous ministerial correspondence, 1945 1948; 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1949 1959; 1949-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board of directors records, 1928 2019; 1928-2019; 14 Folders
    This subseries contains records from the board of directors of the conference. The majority of the records are board reports and minutes, but the subseries also contains correspondence.
    - Board of directors records, 1928 1938; 1928-1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Board of directors records, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Board of directors correspondence, 1993 2004; 1993-2004 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Board of directors retreat, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Board of directors records, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Board of directors records, 2005 2007; 2005-2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Board of directors records, 2008 2010; 2008-2010 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Board of directors records, 2011 2012; 2011-2012 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Board of directors records, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Board of directors records, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Board of directors records, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Board of directors records, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Board of directors records, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Board of directors records, 2018 2019; 2018-2019 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Conference history, 1945 1970; 1945-1970; 5 Folders
    This subseries contains documents and manuscripts related to the history of the conference. The subseries contains three different versions of a 1970 conference history written by James H. Lightbourne.
    - Conference history, 1945 1961; 1945-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Church histories gathered for 150th conference anniversary, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Conference history draft, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Conference history draft, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - History of the Rhode Island Conference manuscript, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual reports and meetings, 1948 2019; 1948-2019; 20 Folders
    This subseries contains both annual reports for the conference as well as the records of the conference's annual and autumnal meetings.
    - Annual reports, 1948 1962; 1948-1962 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Annual reports, 1963 1973; 1963-1973 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Annual meeting, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Annual meeting, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Annual meeting, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Annual meeting, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Autumnal meeting, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Annual meeting, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Autumnal meeting, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Annual meeting, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Autumnal meeting, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Annual meeting, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Autumnal meeting, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Annual meeting, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Autumnal meeting, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Annual meeting, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Autumnal meeting, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Autumnal meeting, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Annual meeting, 2018 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Annual meeting, 2019 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Conference programs and task forces, 1930 2017; 1930-2017; 59 Folders
  This series contains the programmatic records of the Rhode Island Conference. The majority of the records in the series relate to either programs and events sponsored and/or run by the conference and its staff or to task forces convened by the conference. These programmatic records describe in detail the wide variety of activities the conference sponsored throughout its history, especially during the 20th century. The records also show a growing interest in social justice issues throughout the century. The records include meeting minutes and communications from task forces, brochures and programs, event flyers, newsletters, and correspondence.
  - Anne Hutchinson symposium records, 1988 1989; 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Boundary training program, 2008 2017; 2008, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Campaign for our church binder, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Campaign for Our Church booklet, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Center for Theological Education records, 1985 1993; 1985-1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Champlin Foundations grant communications, 1977 2000; 1977-2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Church in society division records, 1994 2000; 1994-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Church renewal task force records, 1974 1975; 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Climate change, 2011 2012; 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Colloquy on covenant, 1988 1990; 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Conscientious objectors correspondence and brochures, 1936 1946; 1936-1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Christian Concerns newsletter, 1985 1995; 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Church and fall foliage bus tour events, 1997 1998; 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Committee on church membership and evangelism minutes, 1975 1998; 1975-1998 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Committee on church membership and evangelism communications, 1987 1992; 1987-1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Congregational and conference life communications, 1994 1998; 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - David Allan Kerr program, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - David Macauley Thanksgiving event, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Disaster preparedness seminar photographs, circa 2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Disaster preparedness planning and seminars, 2001 2003; 2001-2003 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Economic justice paper, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Expanding Horizons journal communications, 1997 1998; 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "Face of Religion" newsclippings, 1965 1980; 1965-1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Family life committee records, 1982 1993; 1982-1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Friends of responsible media records, 1989 1998; 1989, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Golf tournaments, 1994 1999; 1994, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Green Church certificate, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Hispanic consultation project, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Holy land trips, 1987 2001; 1987-2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Holy land travel photographs, circa 2000 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Jeon-buk Presbytery Korean exchange program records, 1995 2000; 1995-2000 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Lay school of theology brochures, 1979 1981; 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Marriage enrichment weekends, 1984 1995; 1984-1995 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Maude Bradley award, 1930 1976; 1930-1976 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Ministers' Association meeting and retreat flyers, 1973 2004; 1973-2004 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Mission Evangélique Baptiste Bethesda DHaïti general administrations building drawings, 1996 (Folder 3)
  - Montana-Rhode Island mission interpreter program records, 1985 1990; 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Moyne Cubbage preaching workshop materials, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Open and affirming task force minutes, 1991 1994; 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Open and affirming task force communications, 1991 2004; 1991-2004 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Organist job descriptions and wage ranges, 1989 1996; 1989-1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Peace task force meeting minutes, 1981 1992; 1981-1992 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Peace task force communications, 1985 1998; 1985-1998 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Pilgrimage retreats, 1987 2001; 1987-2001 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Pilgrimage retreat photographs, circa 2001 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Prison ministry programs, 1992 2002; 1992-2002 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Pro choice task force minutes and workshop, 1984 1991; 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Public education symposium and communications, 1986 1993; 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Public education committee minutes, 1992 1996; 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Radio programs, 1983 2002; 1983-2002 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Representative Pat Schroeder event, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Retired clergy newsletter, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Rhode Island State Council of Churches newsletter, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Social justice committee communications, 1982 1997; 1982-1997 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Social justice committee minutes, 1994 1997; 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Substance abuse task force communications, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Talladega College concert, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Worship experience breakfast program records, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - "Young Adults" correspondence, brochures, and announcements, 1948 1954; 1948-1954 (Box 4, Folder 54)